Alessandro Righi

Curriculum Vitae

Embedded

San Pietro in Cariano 37029, Verona, Italy ☐ +39 349 843 7935 ☑ alessandro.righi@outlook.it ❸ alerighi.it in alerighi ♀ alerighi

Hi! I'm a software engineer living in Verona. I have a strong passion in informatics and electronics. I currently work as a software engineer in IOTINGA, a company specialized in IoT products and industry 4.0. I got a Master's degree in Computer science and engineering with the specialization in cybersecurity at the University of Verona, where I also got a bachelor's degree. In my spare time I'm an instructor for the CyberChallenge.IT program at the University of Verona. I did work as a tutor for the Italian Olympics in Informatics.

reform verona.	Tula Work as a tator for the realian Olympies in informatics.
	Education
2018–2022	Master degree in Computer Science and Engineering, with specialization in Computer Security, $University$ of $Verona$, $109/110$
2015-2018	Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, University of Verona, 110/110 with honors
2010–2015	Diploma of scientific lyceum, ISIS L. Calabrese P. Levi, San Pietro in Cariano (VR), 80/100
	Experience
2020-today	Software engineer, IOTINGA s.r.l., San Martino Buon Albergo (VR)
2021–today	Instructor for the CyberChallenge.IT program, University of Verona
2018-2022	Tutor and software developer for the Italian Olympics in Informatics team
2018-2020	Tutor for the course Programming Challenges, University of Verona
2019–2020	Tutor for the courses Programming I, Bioinformatics, University of Verona
2019–2020	Tutor for the courses Programming II, Informatics, University of Verona
2018–2019	Tutor for the course Programming, Applied Mathematics, University of Verona
	Archivements
2020	Third place at the CyberChallenge.IT national challenge, University of Verona
2020	First place at the local CyberChallenge.IT CTF, University of Verona
2020	35st place at the ICPC-ACM SWERC 2019-2020, Télécom ParisTech, Paris
2019	21st place at the Google HashCode word finals, Google European Headquarter, Dublin
2018	22nd place at the ICPC-ACM SWERC 2018-2019, Télécom ParisTech, Paris
	Languages
Italian	Native speaker
Inglese	Level B1
iligiese	
	Technical skills

Espressif, FreeRTOS App Development of iOS/Android apps with React Native

Backend REST API development, Node.JS, Python, Django, PostgreSQL

Cloud Execllent knowledge of AWS services, serverless, DynamoDB, EC2, ECS, Lambda, IoT Core, IAM, Cloudformation

Firmware development for 32-bit microcontrollers, cloud communication, MQTT, BLE,

Elettronica Digital electronic circuit design, PCB creation with KiCad, fault diagnostic and repair

 $System \quad System \quad S$

Cybersecurity Penetration testing, malware analysis, reverse engineering, CTF Frontend Web app developement with React, CSS, TypeScript, PHP

You can get the latest version of this document here: https://alerighi.it/cv-alessandro-righi.pdf.

Take also a loot at my website https://alerighi.it and my GitHub page https://github.com/alerighi.